thejakartapost.com 2019-12-30

# Privacy Policy - The Jakarta Post

### The Jakarta Post Privacy Policy

_The Jakarta Post_ is committed to protecting your private information while you are using our services, which include the following but are not limited to information sharing and enquiry as well as establishing a general communication line via our platform, et cetera. The terms regulated within the Privacy Policy ("Policy") apply to any and all content material published on our platform, unless stipulated otherwise. The Policy also determines the type of information we collect, the reason we are collecting it, how we may use the information, which party is responsible for the collection and use of your private information and how to keep your information up-to-date. 

By using our website, it is mutually understood that you have read and agree to the terms written in this Policy. However, if you are not familiar with certain terms, you are welcome to contact us. 

This site is owned by The Jakarta Post Digital and is accessible by anyone anywhere in the world. We are the sole manager of the data we collect. Your private information matters to us, therefore we kindly ask you to take the time to read and understand our Policy since it may differ from or be less protective than the laws of your jurisdiction. 

#### Information we collect

We collect certain information to provide better services to all of our users, including – but not limited to – reference sites, IP address, browser type, default language and other (more complex) information such as your particular behavior and preferences while using the site. 

We collect information in the following ways:   

  * Voluntary disclosure. This is information that we require you to provide in order to continue using our services. Such information includes, for example: your name, e-mail address, telephone number, or credit card account information. You are free to choose not to provide your personal information; however, certain services may not be available to you. Your personal details will be collected upon registration, but you may change them at any time as you see fit. 
  * Devices. We use the term “devices” to refer to your hardware model, operating system (and its subsequent) version, as well as other applications on your devices that are accessible online. We may collect data and information about the services you use via your devices such as your actual location, local storage, et cetera. 

#### Use of personal information

Services and user experience. We collect and use your personal information to provide services on, maintain, protect and improve our site. We also use the data to elevate our customers’ experiences, and we do this by conducting a series of research and analysis activities to help us tailor our content display according to your interests and preferences. 

Communication. We will also use your personal information to communicate with you; for example, in the instance that other users are using or sharing your information or account on our platform. We may also send transaction-related messages such as billing reminders and purchase confirmation. Moreover, we will also use your personal information to notify you of our marketing activities (survey) and of our updated services and features. 

Troubleshooting. We respect the choices you make in limiting sharing or visibility settings on your account. We will keep a record of your communication to help you with issues that you may be facing. Nevertheless, rest assured we will always ask for your consent before using your personal information for purposes other than those which have been stipulated within this Policy. 

#### Sharing personal information

We do not share your personal information unless otherwise required in one of the following circumstances. 

  * External proceedings. We may disclose your personal information with a third party, which performs services on our behalf; they are our affiliates, or other trusted businesses or persons. In this case, they will process the information we have collected for us; for example, companies that handle our marketing services, payment processing, data storage, website hosting, or other entities whose expertise may include creating user interface, conducting surveys, et cetera. The information we share with any third party will be processed based solely on our request and instructions; and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of such information and are prohibited from using it for other purposes.   
We maintain a non-disclosure agreement with each of the partners we are affiliated with; and specifically insist that it be issued in compliance with our Policy. However, personal information may be disclosed in the case of merger, acquisition or transaction of companies’ assets, or bankruptcy. 
  * Legal reasons. We reserve the right to disclose your personal information when we are required to do so by law. We will disclose your information in good faith, deeming the action necessary in order to fulfill legal demands, proceedings and other such enforceable request by the authorities. Moreover, with the exceptional purpose of protecting the rights, property or safety of our company, our customers, our users or the public as required by law, we may disclose your personal information. 

#### Children’s personal data

We do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 18 or knowingly allow such persons to provide us with their personal information without verifiable consent of parents or guardians. If you are under 18, we do not allow you to send any information regarding yourself, including your name, address, e-mail, et cetera, unless you have permission from your parents or guardians and personally appeal to us. 

In the event we learn that we collected personal information from anyone under the age of 18 without any consent from parents or guardians, we will delete the information as quickly as possible. Those who are under 18 may also remove or request and obtain removal of information or commentary that they post on our site. 

We encourage you to notify us in the event that you believe we store information from or about anyone under the age of 18, or if you wish to request and obtain removal of information or commentary. 

#### Accessing and updating your personal information

You can review and revise your personal information on our site at any time. Also, please update your information as you see fit. 

We aim to maintain our services in a manner that protects the information from severe destruction. Therefore, we may not immediately delete residual copies of our users’ personal information from our active servers and may not remove whole information from our back-up system. 

#### Cookies and other technology

We (and our partners) may use several technologies to collect and store information, including the use of “cookies” and other similar data-collection methods such as pixel tags, web beacons, et cetera, for certain purposes such as to enable you to identify your browser or devices, to subscribe to our services and to personalize and improve our users’ experiences. 

We also use the technologies to collect and store information when you interact with the services we offer to our partners or other features displayed on our site. 

#### Information security

We treat your personal information as important data. Therefore, we apply the generally accepted industry standards to protect your personal information. For example, when you provide sensitive information on our online registration form, we would encrypt the information using secure socket layer (SSL) technology. However, it is important that you understand any security measure currently available to any internet user cannot guarantee 100 percent protection. 

We would also like to remind you that it is your sole responsibility to keep your password confidential in order to protect your account and personal information. 

#### Compliance and cooperation with regular authorities

We regularly review our Policy compliance against the prevailing law. We welcome any suggestions, complaints or questions you wish to share with us and in that case we will contact you personally to follow-up on them. 

We also maintain a collaborative effort with all regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve potential complaints regarding the transfer of personal information if we are not able to contact our users directly. 

#### Changes to Privacy Policy

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Nevertheless, we will not compromise your rights without your written consent; and we will provide a written notification upon the slightest change in our Policy via our homepage. We encourage you to kindly review this Policy whenever you visit our site. 

For more information, please reach out to us at _info@jakpost.com_
